#### **KEVIN HANARD**

5/15 Battery Square Battery Point 7004 TAS Driver & Forklift Licence

**2** 0477.694.885

<u>kevin.hanard@gmail.com</u>

### **Career Profile**

A logistics professional with five years' experience in transport and freight. I have a proven track record of project management, transport management and team management.

During Covid I spent the last few months learning coding (web development). Also, I have recently been granted Permanent Residency in Australia, I am now looking for a new professional challenge.

### **Career History**

<u>2020 - 2021</u>: **Delivery Driver**, *Australia Post* (Australia)

2017 - 2019 (7 months): Picker & Packer, OfficeMax (Australia)

2019 - 2020 (4 months) Picker & Packer, Winc (Australia)

2017 - 2019 (7 months): Picker & Packer, OfficeMax (Australia)

<u>2016</u> (2 months) : **Despatch Supervisor**, *Manbulloo* LTD (Australia)

2015 - 2016 (3 months): **Packhouse Supervisor**, *Manbulloo* LTD (Australia)

2015 (6 months): **Stacker**, *Koorelah Farms* (Australia)

<u>2012 - 2014</u> (2 years) : **Transport Project Manager**, *DFCA* (France)

<u>2011 - 2012</u> (1 year) : **Logistics Assistant Manager**, *Bosal Distribution* (France)

<u>2011 - 2012</u> (1 year) : **Logistics Assistant**, Warehouse *Grt Gaz* (France)

<u>2007 - 2009</u> (10 months) : **Production & Machine Operator**, *Pasquier* (France)

## **Professional Experience**

<u>From December 2020</u>: **Delivery Driver**, *Australia Post*, Hobart (Australia-TAS)

Planning deliveries and scanning of parcels

- Delivering parcels to customers (130 to 180 per day)
- Providing an excellent customers experience

November 2019 - March 2020 : **Picker & Packer**, *Winc* (Office Supplies), Hobart (Australia-TAS)

- Picking & packing orders

November 2017 - February 2018 & November 2018 - March 2019: Picker & Packer, OfficeMax (Office Supplies), Hobart (Australia-TAS)

- Picking & packing orders

October - November 2016 (2 months): **Despatch Supervisor**, *Manbulloo LTD* (Mango producer), Katherine (Australia-NT)

- Supervised stacking team and forklift drivers (5 people), motivate team members for the busy harvest season, provide training
- Determination of transport requirement and prioritized deliveries
- Ensuring Mangoes are stored, loaded and transported in conditions that will maintain an optimal quality
- Managed despatch (order preparation, despatch documentation, prioritization)
- Oversaw the management of stocks in cool room
- Managed quarantine process for exporting food in Australia

November - January 2015 (3 months): **Packhouse Supervisor**, *Manbulloo LTD* (Mango company), Giru (Australia-QLD)

- Managed stacking team (6 stackers) and forklift driver. Motivate team members for the busy harvest season, provide training
- Coordinated the activities of production and despatch departments. Liaising and coordinating resources, provided support to the despatch supervisor
- Ensured every workers adhere to the company's policies, procedures and strictly respect food safety protocols.
- Ensuring Mangoes are stored (oversaw the management of stock in cool room), loaded and transported in condition that will maintain an optimal quality

<u>2012-2014</u> (2 years) : **Transport Project Manager**, *SNCF Direction Fret Charbon Acier* (Freight transport), Lille (France)

- Developed transport plan: Supervised and coordinated the production of internal departments (involved up to 30 employees) and external customers to meet all logistics requirements. From the customer's needs: working out the itinerary (train paths), setting up trains, locomotives, drivers and required external services to ensure the goods are transported in conditions that will maintain their optimum quality.
- Oversaw the communication of the transport plan. Led meeting and used various tools to share information about the transport flow
- Negotiated with stakeholders to offer the most efficient transport to a reasonable cost
- Risk assessed and planned contingency plan
- Led, prepared and tracked production meeting in National scale (10-20 participants: with quality, production, sales, security department and partners) to improve the flow and achieve better customer satisfaction.
- Within the elaboration of transport flows, ensuring compliance with the rules pertaining to personnel management (occupational health and safety regulations, fatigue management, number of working and driving hours)
- Coordination of the activities associated with the arrival, departure, loading and unloading of transports (including trains, trucks, and any multimodal activities)

<u>2011-2012</u> (1 year) : **Logistics Assistant Manager**, *Bosal Distribution* (Logistics Automobile), Béthune (France)

- Assessed the transport flows, created the new delivery schedule, support for the creation of requirement specification —> optimised the transport flows by reducing costs by 15% (1 M€/year before project, 850 000 € after project) and delivery time (up to 30%)
- Participation to the negotiation with transport companies related to our new transport plan
- Supervised inventory staff (2 people), optimisation (forecasting, ABC, reorder point, new procedure) and management of the inventory
- Worked in a project mode and led small teams in a continuous improvement environment

- Created logistics indicators board (productivity, fiability, target, orders)

2010-2011 (1 year): **Logistics Assistant**, GrtGaz (Gas industry), Paris (France)

- Created logistics procedures (reception, picking, packing, despatching)
- Support for the inventory management
- Developed new litigation management: Developed process, training and the requirement for the new litigation management tool.

<u>2007-2009</u> (10 months): Seasonal work as **Machine Operator**, *Brioche Pasquier* (Food processing industry), Aubigny-en-Artois (France)

- Maintenance machines
- Reception of supplies

### **Education and Training Qualifications**

2020: Training in Web-development: HTML5 / CSS3 / jQuery / Javascript

2018: CPA Foundation: Fundamentals of Business Law / Foundation of Accounting

<u>2018 - 2019</u>: Advanced Diploma of Leadership & Management, VTI, Hobart (Australia)

2017-2018: Diploma of Leadership & Management, TASTAFE, Hobart (Australia)

<u>2012-2014</u>: *Master Logistique Globale (MLG)*: Master's Degree in Logistics, Transport and Team Management, in Faculty of Applied Science, Béthune (France)

<u>2011-2012</u>: Licence professionnel Management Européen de la Chaîne Logistique (MELOG): Bachelor Degree in Logistics, in FAS, Béthune (France)

<u>2009-2011</u>: *DUT Qualité Logistique Industrielle et Organisation (QLIO)*: Two years University technology Degree in Quality, Logistics, Production and Industrial Organization, in University Institute of Technology, Béthune (France)

#### **Others Skills**

<u>Languages</u>: French (Native) and English (IELTS 7- PTE 82) <u>Tools</u>: Microsoft Office, AS400, SAP, PRONTO, RF Scanner

## **Interests**

**Bushwalking & Camping** 

Reading: National Geographic, A Song of Ice and Fire, Hyperion, Dune Travel (USA, Canada, New Zealand, Italy, Indonesia, Vietnam, Malaysia..)

# Referee

Phillipe NcNamara, Supervisor Back to School, OfficeMax 0427 147 887